# SPICER MATTHEWS

901 Brutscher Street, D112, Newberg, OR, 97132

Phone: 503-451-0062 E-Mail: me@spicermatthews.com

# **Summary**

Highly accomplished software engineer / sysadmin with experience working on a range of projects, from the needs of large organizations to early-stage startups, in the areas of designing, building, testing, and managing large systems consisting of backend servers, databases, APIs and cloud deployments.

# **Experience**

#### Gladly (https://gladly.io) - Founding Engineer

Jan. 2023 - Current

- Managed a small team of engineers, and outside vendors
- Worked with CEO to build new features, set the company's technical direction
- Software development: PHP / Laravel, Nodejs, Golang, React, Serverless, DynamoDB, Firebase
- Sysadmin work: Docker, AWS, Ansible, Vercel, Redis, DynamoDB

### **Freelance Software Developer**

Dec. 2022 - Jan. 2023

- Development / IT / Software as a Service provider
- Software development: PHP / Laravel, Golang, Craftcms, React, Angular, Nodejs
- Sysadmin work: Docker, AWS, Ansible, LAMP Stack

#### Tenchi Security (https://tenchisecurity.com) - Senior Software Engineer

Feb. 2022 - Dec. 2022

- Software development: Angular 2+, NodeJs
- Sysadmin work: Docker, AWS, Serverless
- Team lead for frontend development

#### Haul Hub Inc. (https://www.haulhub.com) - Software Engineer

April 2021 - Dec. 2021

- Software development: Ruby on Rails, React
- Worked on a number of teams supporting bug fixes, and new feature requests
- · Worked with and help supported large overseas development teams
- Challenged by software tasks working on legacy software, while also building new greenfield software

### Prospect Ag (https://prospectag.com) - Founding Tech Partner

Feb. 2021 - Sept. 2021

- District Capital pivoted into Prospect Ag upon the pivot I was asked to be the founding CTO
- We build a prototype of the core product to demo to investors
- I was very involved with pitching a number of venture capital investors; obtained a number of meetings
- Learned tons about agricultural and the data science needs for this industry
- Secured \$350,000 in investor commitments

## District Capital (https://districtcapital.com) - Head of Engineering

Oct. 2019 - Feb. 2021

- Manage software engineering team and design team
- Work directly with the executive team to set tech roadmap
- Represent company engineering initiatives to venture capital investors
- Manage technical aspects of a 200 million dollar partnership with Citi and Axonic Capital
- Software development: Angular 2+, Golang, Craftcms, PHP
- Sysadmin work: Docker, Ansible, LAMP Stack
- Helped raise millions in venture capital investment

### District Capital (https://districtcapital.com) - Senior Software Engineer

Jan. 2019 - Oct. 2019

- Software development: Angular 2+, Golang, Craftcms, PHP
- Sysadmin work: Docker, Ansible, LAMP Stack
- Support team to build a commercial lending software platform

### Vector Media Group (https://vectormediagroup.com) - Full Stack Developer

July 2016 - Dec. 2018

- CMS Development Craftcms, Expression Engine, and Custom Built
- Sysadmin work: Docker, AWS, Ansible, LAMP Stack
- Lead programmer on big-budget projects while working remotely
- Build large custom applications for high traffic customers

# Cloudmanic Labs (http://cloudmanic.com) - Lead Engineer

Jun. 1998 - July 2016

- Development / IT / Software as a Service provider
- Software development: PHP, Golang, Craftcms
- Sysadmin work: Docker, AWS, Ansible, LAMP Stack
- Built https://skyclerk.com Accounting Software
- Built <a href="https://options.cafe">https://options.cafe</a> Stock & Options Trading Platform

### Elevation Fitness (http://elevationfit.com) - Senior Staff Engineer

Jan. 2012 - July 2016

- Maintained https://elevationfit.com Software for Personal Trainers
- Scaled to the software to support exponential growth user growth
- Software development: PHP, Golang, Craftcms, Angular
- Sysadmin work: Docker, AWS, Ansible, LAMP Stack
- Lead the technical sales process Helped closed big deal with Cincinnati Reds
- Key advisor to CEO on long term strategy

### Downstream (http://downstream.com) - Lead Systems Developer

Jan. 2011 - Oct. 2011

- Built custom content management systems for fortune 100 companies
- Managed local & remote teams of contractors
- Project managed wireframing and design
- System architect of core products

### Elevation Fitness (http://elevationfit.com) - CTO

Feb. 2008 - Jan. 2011

- Built <a href="https://elevationfit.com">https://elevationfit.com</a> Software for Personal Trainers
- Lead the technical sales process Helped closed big deal with Cincinnati Reds
- Key advisor to CEO on long term strategy

#### Portland State University (http://its.pdx.edu) - Software Developer

Nov. 2005 - Oct. 2010

- Build and managed software that archived traffic data (massive database)
- Set & implemented system architecture
- Advised staff & student workers on web technologies
- Frontend & backend programming

#### **Matthews Etc. Construction – Software Developer**

Jun. 2005 - Jan. 2008

- Built custom software application to manage and optimize construction business
- Worked with project managers and developers to use custom software to build for 30% less
- Built algorithms to predict what materials a job site would need in advance

### Portland State University (http://cat.pdx.edu) - Lead Linux Admin

Nov. 2001 - Sept. 2005

- Helped bring Linux to Portland State by educating staff, and advocating for adoption
- Grew the department from 20 150 supported machines
- Built systems to manage and deploy Linux computers
- Managed high volume production servers

### Education

#### **Portland State University - Bachelors Of Science**

June 2007

Took extensive courses in computer science, computer engineering, and business.

### **Skills**

#### Advanced Technical

Golang, Php, Laravel, Ansible, Docker, Vue.js, React, Craftcms, Expression Engine, NodeJs, C, C++, Java, Javascript, Jquery, AngularJs, MySql, Postgresql, Git, Beanstalkd, Nginx, Phonegap / Cordova, Titanium, Amazon AWS, Linux / Unix Administration

#### Basic Technical

Objective – C (Apple Products), Swift, Android, Ruby on Rails, Cake PHP, Zend Php, Symfony

### **Hobbies & Non-Professional Actives**

Snowboarding, Tennis, Skateboarding, Investing (stock market), Student of Business, Student of Programming Technologies